Vladislav Baimurzin

CONTACTS

Email: baimurzin.719@gmail.com

Cell: +79274484448

Personal information

Date of birth: 18 June 1995

Marital status: single

Foreign Languages: English: written and spoken

Summary of Qualifications

- Bachelor's degree in Applied Informatics
- Over 4 years of experience in development of Windows and Linux based solutions: Client/Server applications, GUI, libraries.
- Strong development skills in Java SE/EE for Windows/Linux platform
- Strong in development Web Sevices (SOAP, REST)
- Hands-on Web application development skills (AngularJS, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
- Hands-on experience Agile development methodologies (Scrum, Kanban)

Tools & Technology Expertise

Operating Systems	Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)
Programmin g Languages	JavaSE, JavaEE, JavaScript, Unix shells, PHP
Java Frameworks	Spring, JPA, JSP, Hibernate ORM
PHP Frameworks	Symfony, Laravel
JavaScript lib/ frameworks	JQuery, AngularJS, WebRTC, NodeJS, ExpressJS, PhantomJS

Web Services	SOAP, REST
Version Control	Git
Data Base	MySQL, PostgreSQL
SDE & Tools and Other technologies	GWT, Mockito, Junit, Freemarker, Intellij IDEA, Tomcat, Maven, Jenkins

Project Experience

MERA, Kazan

1. Outsourcing Avaya company, CRM Object Routing, Senior Java Developer

2017 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Development of a solution for extending Avaya Contact Center
- Full responsibility for backend part: analysis of requirements, requirements specification, implementation, verification.
- Development architecture design for this solution.
- Suggesting ideas and implementation to make better scalability.
- Development event-driven architecture using Gigaspaces XAP Datagrid
- Integration with external vendors to build communication between Avaya call centers and CRM such as Salesforce.
- Presenting this solution to Avaya's managers from SF, CA
- Solving problem with external partners companies in order to meet a project deadline.
- Troubleshooting and bugfix.

Key technologies: J2EE, Spring, PostgreSQL, Gigaspaces XAP, web sockets, streaming API, REST API, Unix shell, HTTP/HTTPS, Intellij IDEA, Linux, Agile (Scrum)

Self-employed, Freelance

1. 2013 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Development of web services.
- Database schema design. (Postgresgl, mysgl)
- Development of secure application(preventing XSS, SQL Injection and so on)
- Configuring server VPS/VDS on Linux(Ubuntu server 16.04 14.04)
- Reverse Engineering/Sniffing network traffic of software application's, mobile applications. Writing private APIs and building libraries on this private application's API on top of both protocol HTTP and HTTPS.
- Bypassing some types of security such as secure connection(HTTPS), SSL certificate pinning.
- Building teams. Recruiting persons, partners.
- CEO of Nova Entertainment Ltd company.

 CEO of InnoCorp Ltd company(winner of BI IT Park Kazan with an office in Kazan IT park) with a team of 5 persons and several people on outsourcing.

IAT. Innovative Advertising Technologies GmbH, Germany, Remote

1. CValue - HR-recruiting service, Full-stack web developer, 2016 - 2017

Responsibilities:

- Development of HR-recruiting web service.
- Building frontend based on jQuery, VideoJS, WebRTC.
- Building backend based on PHP, Symfony, NodeJS.
- Started with colleague from scratch, suggesting solutions and approaches.
- Wrote my own js library plugin for video webrtc communication.
- Troubleshooting and bugfix

Data Armor, Kazan

1. SMM automative platform, Software engineer, 2016

Responsibilities:

- Development a SMM service for business proposals based on Facebook API, Twitter API
- Building frontend based on jQuery.
- Building backend based on Laravel.
- Choosing an approach how to solve tasks. Suggesting and implementing software.
- Troubleshooting and bugfix

Telecor

1. Project for government customer, Java developer, 2015

Responsibilities:

- Development of Spring based system for government customer.
- Development new frontend and backend part of application.
- Support and bug fixing for existing functionality based on Hibernate,
 Spring and ExtJS on frontend. Working with PostgresQL.
- Suggested to use new technologies for administration section of application - AngularJS. And started to implement new module from scratch using Spring Framework and Angularjs.
- Troubleshooting and bugfix

Digital Zone

1. Internal product, Java intern, 2014

Responsibilities:

- Development of Spring based system with GWT.
 Troubleshooting and bugfix
 Implementing new module from scratch

Key technologies: Spring, PostgreSQL, Hibernate, GWT

Education

2013 - 2017 - Kazan Federal University Bachelor's degree in Applied Informatics